JEREMY GUZMAN

New York, NY 11101 | (917) 855-3536 | Jeremy.r.Guzman@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremyguzman/

SUMMARY

As a seasoned sales professional with a passion for technology, I am now transitioning into the field of full stack software development. With a strong background in customer service and relationship management, I possess the ability to understand client needs and effectively communicate with team members. I have experience with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript with a focus using React.js. Additionally, my experience in sales has taught me the importance of persistence, problem solving, and working collaboratively towards a common goal. I am excited to bring these skills and knowledge to a new role in software development and continue to grow and learn in the tech field.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems: Windows 11, MAC OS, Unix/Linux

Databases: SQL Server, SalesForce, MongoDB

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Python, Express.js, React.js

Software Applications: Microsoft Office, Github, Git, Visual Studio Code, Node.js, Mongoose, Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Per Scholas | Software Engineering | New York, NY (Remote) CUNY City College | Bachelor of Arts - Philosophy | New York, NY

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Perscholas, Remote - Aug 2022 - Nov 2022

Student - Software engineering

- Engineering modern applications with HTML/CSS Javascript, React, Node, MongoDB & Express
- Building web apps from scratch to full deployment.
- Collaborating with cohort to build full stack MERN applications
- Resiliently problem solving through bugs and coding obstacles to better polish skills

Property Manager / Developer - Kingston, NY August 2019 - Current

Skills & Tasks applied to succeed include:

- Built out a pipeline method to analyze & underwrite potential properties in minutes isolating the best investments to make offers in a fast paced market | data included: county tax rolls, competitive rents, mortgage rates, renovation costs etc
- Increased after renovation value capitalization rate of first property by +100%
- Sourced, vetted & hired contractors. Oversaw renovations & budget
- Marketed finished rentals. Qualifying, screening, preparing leases & signing renters at market rents
- Managed project from start to finish from all levels including: maintenance requests, sourcing, staffing, setting expectations

OnDeck, New York, NY Oct. 2016 - Sep. 2019

Loan Advisor - Direct Sales

- Closed new business consistently at or above quota level via phone & email
- Managed and maintained a very active pipeline daily
- Advocated for both parties as sole contact between customer & operations/underwriters while collecting documents and closing term loans up to \$500,000 & lines of credit up to \$100,000.
- Responsible for +\$8,000,000 in small business loans in turn helping hundreds of small businesses across the U.S. and Canada

IQPC, New York, NY Aug. 2015 - Oct. 2016

Account Manager - Delegate Acquisitions

- Full cycle sales for targeted networking events in industries including pharmaceutical, automotive, energy and defense
- Consistently closed new business above monthly quota of \$20,000 in revenue via phone & email with C-suite targets
- Forged relationships with High Profile Executive talent for speaking roles at industry events
- Strategized with marketing and production to deliver a better product

MetLife Premier Client Group, New York, NY Sept. 2014 - June 2015

Business Development Manager

- Cold calling, qualifying & setting meetings with prospects of two financial planners
- Actively researching prospects in pipeline / building prospect profiles for financial planning meetings
- generated 50+ meetings per month
- Developed and implemented a 3 day best practices call-and-sales training program for Interns